Rajesh Kumar Thankaraj

Technical Engineer

As a Technical Engineer having 7 years of Industry experience which includes Banking and Financial Domain and Application Support. Specialized in SQL, Front end development and Superior customer service skills. Responsible for leading a 4 member team and acting as an offshore Lead. Logical thinker. Puzzle solver. Quick learner. MERN Stack enthusiast with having considerable knowledge in JavaScript.



	4.0		_		
\sim	than	Vara:	വ	amai	l.com
\sim	ullall	NOI O		ylliai	LCOIII

+91 9447328297

Thiruvananthapuram, India

in linkedin.com/in/rajesh-kumar-thankaraj-204567177

github.com/RajeshKumarThankaraj

WORK EXPERIENCE

Technical Engineer Finastra

03/2018 - Present

Trivandrum

Roles & Responsibilities

- Acting in a key position to lead the offshore Mortgagebot TECH & QA team.
- Understanding the Banking Domain in detail and implement the functionalities accordingly.
- Expertise knowledge in writing SQL scripts for Mortgage & Lending Products.
- Experience in integration and functional testing.
- Fixing the UI change requests and working on the new functionalities on demands.
- Team-oriented, individual and self-starter who excels at learning new processes, business functions and logic.
- Ability to simultaneously work on multiple deliverable by prioritising the assigned tasks.

Sr. System Engineer

Cognizant Technology Solutions

09/2014 - 07/2017

Coimbatore

Roles & Responsibilities

- Worked on a client-facing environment in an Application Support Team, responsible for end-to-end Application Priority incidents
- The ultimate ownership for the customer issues and coordinating with L2/L3 Technical team and Business team for the application enhancements.
- Application and Escalation 1st level POC for the Cognizant Revenue forecasting Application.
- Sharing reports and data analysis on all the delivery parameters to the Customers and Executive Leadership.
- Driving the SLA Adherence of the team and maintaining the Response and Resolution SLA.
- Have developed a strong interpersonal and communication skill by handling customers and support calls.
- Closely working with the Automation team to achieve the cost/resource optimization target.
- Key person in contributing, updating and approving KEDB (Known Error Database) documents for the resolutions.

SKILLS

SQL HTML JavaScript CSS

Bootstrap React JS JSON

REST API Testing Jira

Application Support BMC Remedy

SharePoint Admin PowerShell

Service Now TestTrack

Data Structures MS Office ITIL

EDUCATION

B.E in Computer Science & Engg Nehru Institute of Technology - Anna University, Chennai

07/2009 - 04/2013 CGPA 6.13

M.Tech in Software Engineering BITS Pilani

07/2021 - 04/2023

AWARDS

URLA Cursher (06/2020 - 12/2020)

For outstanding performance of URLA Project deliverable.

Hi-Five Shout of Praise (06/2019 - 06/2020)

 Major contributor for the Finastra Site Level Employee Engagements Activities for FY 2019-20

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sr. System Engineer Cognizant Technology Solutions

07/2017 - 12/2017

Coimbatore

Roles & Responsibilities

- Environmental Support Analyst for the MetLife Insurance Applications
- Handling application deployments in various DEV & QA environments.
- Handling Priority tickets by coordinating different teams and owns the incidents or service requests and update the incident status.
- Monitoring application health status, logs and Providing RCA to the customer for any issues.
- Smoke Testing the application regularly after deployments and update the DEV teams.

CERTIFICATES

Completed JavaScript Essential Training on Linkedin Learning (06/2021 - 08/2020)

Achieved Gold Badge (5 star) from HackerRank for SQL (09/2020)

Completed HTML, CSS Training on Linkedin Learning (04/2021 - 06/2020)

Completed Cognizant Internal ITIL Foundation V3 certifications. (09/2014 - 08/2015)

AWARDS

Associate of the Quarter (01/2017 - 03/2017) Cognizant

For top Performer of the quarter across the BU

LANGUAGES

English

Full Professional Proficiency

Tamil

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Malayalam

Full Professional Proficiency

Hindi

Limited Working Proficiency

HOBBIES

Travel

Puzzles

Riddina